trustedplaces.com 2010-01-02

# Privacy Policy - TrustedPlaces - Local Reviews of Restaurants, Pubs, Bars, Clubs & More

## Trustedplaces Privacy Policy 

( _last updated: 15 September 2008_ ) 

Welcome to trustedplaces, and congratulations for clicking on our Privacy Policy, you are probably one of the very few people who have decided to read them, and we thank you for that!

Trustedplaces has developed this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate its firm commitment to the privacy of your data. We’ve read 1984 by George Orwell and don’t like the idea of “big brother” so we strongly believe that your personal data should stay private. All our activities with reference to your data are governed by the Data Protection Act 1998. 

Trustedplaces is committed to safeguarding the privacy of your data whilst providing you with a personalised, fun, and valuable service. This Privacy Policy explains when and how personal information is collected, used, disclosed and protected with respect to trustedplaces. By using trustedplaces, you consent to the privacy practices described in this Policy, as modified from time to time by us. Please carefully revise this Policy periodically to review any changes made to it.

**What is Personal Information?**  
Personal information is defined as information that specifically identifies an individual such as a username, name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, or other account number, and information about that individual's activities when directly linked to that person such as information about his or her use of trusteplaces. Personal information also includes demographic information such as date of birth, gender, geographic area and preferences when such information is linked to other personal information that identifies you. Essentially personal information is what makes you unique and special ;-)

Personal information does not include "aggregate" information. Aggregate information is data we collect about a group or category of places, products, services or customers, from which individual customer identities have been removed. In other words, information about how you use a service may be collected and combined with information about how others use the same service. Aggregate data helps us understand trends and our users' needs so that we can better consider new features or otherwise tailor trustedplaces. 

We collect credit or debit card information to process payments but we do not store those details.

**Personal Information We Collect**   
We collect personal information in a number of ways when you visit our web site. For example, we collect personal information when you: 

  * register and set up an account; 
  * sign up to any of our e-mail newsletters; 
  * discussion topics you create in our “discussion forum”; 
  * post a review or; 
  * contact us by e-mail for any reason. 

When you visit our web site, some information is also automatically collected, such as your computer's Internet Protocol (IP) address, your computer's operating system, the browser type, the address of a referring web site, and timestamp. We treat this information as personal information if we combine it with or link it to any of the identifying information mentioned above. Otherwise, it is used in the aggregate only. 

**How We Use Personal Information?**   
In general, we use personal information to process your requests and provide you with service or to inform you about other products or services we think will be of interest. When we use personal information in our marketing efforts, we provide you with options (See Controlling Your Personal Information below) and do not disclose the information to third parties except as described in this Policy. Personal information provided online may be linked together or merged with other personal information so that we may better understand your needs and inform you about our products or services and those of our partners. In addition, if we receive information from third parties with whom we have business relationships, we may combine this information with the other personal information we maintain about you. In either case, this Policy governs this information.

Browser-type related information, IP address, requested URL, referring URL, and timestamp data help us diagnose problems with our server, administer trustedplaces, and otherwise provide the highest possible level of service to you. In addition, we use this information to perform statistical analyses of user behaviour and characteristics in order to measure interest in and use of the various areas of the site and to inform advertisers of such information as well as the number of users that have been exposed to, or clicked on, their advertising banners.

Additionally trustedplaces uses the information obtained from cookies (see the Cookies section below) for several purposes. The cookies enable us to understand your own personal preferences and tailor your experience on trustedplaces by using those preferences. Trustedplaces also uses cookies to track user trends and patterns. The information which trustedplaces receives from cookies enables us to modify and improve trustedplaces to meet the needs of our users, including you.

When users provide trustedplaces with registration information such as name, email address and postal address, this data can be matched with cookie data, if cookies have been set to be received. This means trustedplaces is able to match an identifiable user with specific usage of trustedplaces. This information would be used by trustedplaces only.

**Content, Reviews, and Ratings**   
You can publish reviews, comments, ratings on all sorts of content on trustedplaces, whether the content was created by you, in conjunction with other users, or simply by other users. Members can choose to rate places or other reviews, and to connect to other members.

Your reviews are displayed publicly unless you change the default configuration. Your username is automatically displayed with reviews, ratings and comments you publish, and if other members choose to, they can receive email notifications of your publications or publish their own comments and ratings to your reviews.

We use your reviews to personalise the site and identify/feature popular members. For example, we may promote most popular reviews and members. While we don't expect to transfer the complete review and member database to others, we use the database throughout our networks and to generate results for others.

**Controlling your Personal Information**  
You should be aware that when you voluntarily disclose personally identifiable information (e.g., username, e-mail address) via reviews, comments, messages, discussion forums, postings, or in other areas of the trustedplaces, that information, along with any substantive information disclosed in your communication, can be collected and correlated and used by third parties and may result in unsolicited messages from other posters or third parties. Such activities are beyond the control of trustedplaces. Please do not post any personal information on trusteplaces or in other areas that you expect to keep private.

As a registered trusteplaces user, you can modify your personal information at any time by accessing the "Edit Profile" section of the site. If you do not want to receive e-mail from us you can change your notification settings within the “My Profile” section of the site. Also, upon your request, trusteplaces will use commercially reasonable efforts to functionally remove you and your personal information from the site; however, it may be impossible to remove your entry without some residual information being retained by trusteplaces. Registered users who wish to close their account should contact [admin@trusteplaces.com](mailto:admin@trusteplaces.com).

**Sharing of Personal Information**  
We do not sell, rent or share personal information with third parties without your prior consent except in the limited circumstances described in this policy. We may share personal information with third-party vendors who assist us in performing functions necessary to operate our business. These functions may include, without limitation, Website hosting, credit card transaction processing and data entry. We limit the information shared with our third-party vendors to that which we believe is necessary to carry out those functions. Moreover, we require them to comply with our privacy practices, and not to use the information for other purposes except as required by law.

In addition, we may disclose personal information in the good faith belief that we are lawfully authorised to do so, or that doing so is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process or authorities, respond to any claims, or to protect the rights, property or personal safety of trustedplaces, our users, our employees or the public. Information about our users, including personal information, may be disclosed or transferred as part of, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets or acquisition but they will be legally bound to keep the information secure and only to use it consistent with this policy in the event of the deal proceeding. Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personal information when posting reviews or other content onto trustedplaces, this information may be collected and used by others. You agree that we bear no responsibility for any such disclosures. We recommend you be cautious in giving out personal information to others in public online forums.

**Cookies**  
Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer's hard drive by your web browser and identify you as a unique user. This allows you a more personalised service when you revisit us. The cookie allows us to find out about your last visit.  We use cookies to refine our site and simplify the user experience. For example, the use of cookies allows registered users to enter our site without explicitly typing in their username/email address and password every time.

Some advertisers may use the cookie technology when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through their Google AdSense program) some information including your IP address, your ISP, and the browser used when you visit our site.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. This process is usually used for geo-targeting purposes only and/or for showing relevant ads based on specific topics that you as web user is searching.

Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to its users, based on their interests ("interest based targeting").

DART cookies are used for ad serving through Google's DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements).

This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests ("interest-based targeting") and the ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history.

DART uses "non personally identifiable information". It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers.

You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting [DART Ad-Serving and Search Cookie Opt-Out](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx).

Users may also opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but usually you can alter the settings of your browser to prevent automatic acceptance if you prefer. If you’d prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies (details can be found at [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)). You should be aware that if you choose not to receive our cookies, we cannot guarantee that our website will be as functional as if you do receive cookies. 

**Security**  
Trustedplaces is concerned for the security of data. Your trustedplaces account is password-protected. To protect the confidentiality of personal information, you must keep your password confidential.

Trustedplaces tries very hard to protect our users’ information. We use industry standard measures to protect your information that is stored within our database. We limit the access to your information to those employees who need access to perform their job function such as our customer service personnel. Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorised disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy. Trustedplaces is constantly reviewing the security measures required to prevent third parties or any unauthorised identity from accessing any data that it holds.

**Global Access to Personal Information**  
Please be aware that if you do post personal information on our website it is accessible worldwide including in countries that do not have adequate data protection laws by EU standards.

**Links to Other Websites**   
Links from our website to third parties or to other sites are provided for your convenience.  Any personal information you provide on the linked pages is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's privacy policy, so we are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of websites to which we link and we recommend you read them before disclosing any personal information. 

**Your Comments or Concerns**  
We always welcome feedback from our users. If you have any comments or concerns about this privacy policy or would like to contact us for any reason, you may reach us at [info@trustedplaces.com](mailto:info@trustedplace.com).

**Terms and Modification to this Privacy Policy**  
By using the website, you signify your agreement to the terms of our Privacy Policy.  Trustedplaces may modify this Privacy Policy at any time and you should check our Privacy Policy periodically to ensure that you are aware of any changes to it since your continued use of website is deemed to constitute your consent to any changes to it.
